# **Matheswaaran**

# **Full stack Developer**

About Me

With over 4 years of experience as a fullstack developer, I've built and worked on a variety of projects from Chennai to the United States. In agile development, works closely with the Design, Backend, and QA teams. Strong background in web application analysis, development, deployment, and debugging.

**Experience** 

Testpress / Senior Developer

NOV 2021 - MAR 2022, CHENNAI

**NFN Labs /** Frontend Developer

JUN 2018 - OCT 2021, CHENNAI

Tools / Languages

**GCP Cloud Functions** HTML5, CSS, Js **NodeJs** AWS EC2, S3, ELB Lambda functions GCP Cloud Storage ReactJs Hasura, Netlify REST APIs, GraphQL Postgres, DynamoDB **API** Gateway AWS Cloud Watch Git Firebase GCP BigQuery

Projects Worked on **Learning Management App - Web / Testpress** 

→ Testpress is an online exam and learning platform founded with a vision of making learning fun and interesting.

Tech: Javascript, Tailwind CSS, Python, Django, AWS Lambda, S3, EC2, Postgres, Cloud Watch

Link: https://www.testpress.tech

#### OroCorp / NFN Labs

- → Oro is a Fin-Tech app that connects financial institutions with users to provide accurate information of the gold loans and rates.
- → Built the web admin interface and Oro partner software along with the team. Used Hasura and Netlify functions for backend

Tech: ReactJs, Tailwind CSS, Hasura, Cloud Functions, Cloud Storage, GraphQL, Firebase

Link: <a href="https://orocorp.in">https://orocorp.in</a>

### Avalara / NFN Labs

- → Avalara is cloud-based tax compliance solutions to handle every transaction in the world.
- → Built the developer portal and API documentation for Avalara APIs and products from scratch within 12 weeks using NextJs and SSR.

Tech: NextJs, Context API, Tailwind CSS, Swaggers, Cloud Functions, BigQuery, API Gateway

Link: https://developer.avalara.com

#### **Breadcrumb** / NFN Labs

- → Breadcrumb is an Ed-Tech app that helps the children to organize their learning using an iPad app with adult supervision.
- → Built the web admin portal, Learning Centers portal and Parents portal for breadcrumb. Used charts for clear understanding of the progress in the respective portals

**Tech:** ReactJs, Redux, GraphQL, Netlify, JWT, Recharts, AWS Lambda, Postgres, ELB, Cloud Watch

Link: <a href="https://learnwithbreadcrumb.com">https://learnwithbreadcrumb.com</a>

### Monday Monk / NFN Labs

- → Monday Monk is a wellness and fitness regime app, which focuses on mental, physical and emotional growth rather than generic exercises.
- → Strategized, built and deployed the web admin app from scratch within 10 weeks using ReactJs, Hasura and GraphQL.

Tech: ReactJs, Context API, Hasura, GraphQL, Netlify, Puppeteer, JWT

Link: https://developer.avalara.com

#### Vookmark / NFN Labs

- → Vookmark allows users to bookmark videos across the web and mobile and watch it later on browser, Apple TV, iPhone, iPad or Android devices.
- → Built features for the bookmarking videos from facebook, youtube, tiktok, vimeo and instagram into Vookmark app.

Tech: Javascript, HTML5, Netlify, Chrome Extensions, Google Ads Integration

Link: <a href="https://vookmark.co">https://vookmark.co</a>

#### **Education**

### PSNA College of Engg and Tech / B.Tech Information Technology

JUL 2014 - MAY 2018. DINDIGUL

Passed out with 72.8% (CGPA: 7.28)

## Notable

#### 1<sup>st</sup> prize at Smart India Hackathon 2018

# Achievements

- → Built a prototype for a common scheme portal for all states in India and an admin portal to manage those schemes.
- → Won first 1st prize with a cash reward of ₹ 1 lakh from Ministry of Social Justice and Empowerment, Govt. of India.

#### Funding for development at Smart India Hackathon 2017

- → Helped build and deploy a human resource management application with the help of MECON limited and Ministry of Steel, Govt. of India.
- → Got funding of ₹4 lakh for development and implementation form Ministry of steel, Govt. of India